Hello, my name is Glen, I am a health
insurance advisor. I am from Thrissur, just like Patna. Today is a
comparison video about health insurance policies. Especially if you are an
NR status person,
try to watch the entire video without skipping it.
[Music]
Especially in today's video,
we are going to show you
a comparison video about health insurance policies that can be considered by those with NR A status.
Before getting into the video, let me explain a
few general things that those with NR
status should understand.
Many people ask when taking health insurance.
People with NR A status often ask whether they
need to take health insurance
.
I understand three things.   If
we have a
critical illness when we first settle down in our country, such as
cancer or a stroke,
we may not be able to
afford health insurance at that time
.  So, if
we
have taken out health insurance while we are in NR status, we will be covered if
we have a critical illness like this in the future
.  So that's the main
reason why we, as NRAs, are taking out health insurance early
.  Because we never know
when these critical things will come into our lives
.  And the second thing I
realized is that there is a
waiting period for health insurance.  Now, the
waiting period for some illnesses is two or three years.  So, when
we settle down in the country,
we will have all this covered.  We
will not have any waiting period.
And the third thing we know is
that in our country, we can easily
see a doctor and
get
treatment
.  But from outside, the
treatment expenses are also very
low.  But many people outside say that it is
extremely difficult to get an appointment to see a treatment doctor here and that the
treatment expenses are very
high.  So, these
three things are the reason why we, who have an NR
status, are saying that we should
take out health insurance on time. Another thing to
note is that we do not get
all A to Z and
all treatment coverage
here like in the Gulf or outside. We
only get treatment expenses in India if we are admitted. When we
call in the Gulf, many people say that just by
showing the card,
we get all the treatment expenses and
our scanning
covered by health insurance.
But that is not the case in our country. In our country,
we get treatment only if we are admitted or inpatient. Pay
attention to that.
Similarly, the
health insurance we
take in our country can
only be used in India. Even if we are in NR
status, we
cannot use it outside. This is why
we, who
have NR status, should try to take out
health insurance on time.
Secondly,
what is the question that many people ask?
Documents are required. What are the things that people
with NR status need to pay attention to when taking health insurance?
As a main, we need our passport
details, as well as visa, now if we
have an OC card, then the OC card details, then as a main,
they
ask for the details of the entry exit stamp, then the PAN card, then the
foreign address proof, that is, now the
details of gas or electricity or rent agreement, they ask for the foreign address
proof, then the
NRI or NRO bank
details for a period of six months,
when we submit the insurance, and fifthly,
an NRI questionnaire. These are the
details that we need to
pay attention to when taking it as an NRI. We need to pay
attention to the documents.
Then when we make the payment, if we
want the NRI discount,
we have to make the payment from the NRI or NRO account.
So these are the things that we generally pay
attention to. And similarly, the
third thing that many people ask is, do
we
have any medical history or do we have any diseases? So
what should people with such diseases pay
attention to when
taking NR insurance? Usually, when we take health insurance, if we have such a
condition, we have to
disclose it. If we
have any pre-existing conditions,
we have to mention it. When we are
NR, if we have our Indian
mobile number, usually the
insurance company calls us and they
come to us through telemedicine. They
call and ask if we have
any diseases or
what is the situation. Since we are
NRIs, if you have an
Indian number, give us your Indian number
or we can arrange a
call to your NRI number.
Especially mentioning the issues is
very important.
So these are the things that
we should pay attention to as a general person. Let's
go into the video in detail. Today, we are considering four health
insurance policies
for those with A status. One is the
HDZOD Optima Secure
plan of ICC.  Today we will be comparing products from four companies: Alavate Appanavopi's
Reshow 3.0, Black KLS's
Ultimate.  The
main feature of these four companies is the
discount.  Now that we have looked at this policy,
we can
now look at HDCR Optima Secure and
get a discount of around 40 percent. If we take three years together on health insurance
premium, a
discount of around 50 percent is available. If we look at ICC Elevate, we
get a discount of around 25 percent. If Anyavappa's
ratio is in black, it is around 15
percent, if it is ultimate, it is around 15
percent. Recently,
Aditya Pulla's
Active One plan
has also brought a discount, but
we have not taken a comparison vehicle here.
Secondly, if we
talk about its premium,
now I am just taking the premium for a 40-35 year old
husband and wife together. If we
look at HDC for a coverage of 10 lakhs, we can take this one CAT,
this is the premium of Kerala.
All the rates that come as basic have been taken in this. The
premium comes out to 14350.  For
10 lakhs,
we can change this sum as per our requirement. I
am taking this just to get an idea. If we
look at an HDC, the premium that comes with both of them is Rs. 14350.
But if we
look at HDC here, if we take 10 lakhs from Devon to IP,
we will get a coverage of 10 lakhs from Devon. If we
look at IC Helvet, if
we apply NR discount, the
premium
comes to Rs. 450. If we
look at Devop, the discount is about Rs. 13528. If the
premium after NRI discount is in Kerala, then after
taking 9218 and looking at this, as mentioned in the
comparative, there is a
lot of difference in the premium after applying NR discount.
Then,
one thing to
keep in mind when we take a policy like this is that if we take
a three-year and
five-year premium together, it is
always better because
especially  When we
take NR status, if we take these NRI
documents for three years as mentioned,
we will need NRI documents for three years
or if we
take one year,
we will have to submit these NRI documents every year. So, if it is
possible as mentioned,
we can take it for three years or five years together.
We can also apply for a discount along with it.
Similarly, another thing is that if
we look at the IP HD
circle, all the family
members must be in NR status,
but only
we get the discount. Another
thing is that if we are in ICC Salvatore,
only one of us, the proposer, needs to be in
NRA status for this
discount to be applicable. If we
look at Appa Nivop, we get this discount only if all the
members have NR status. However, if we
look at Kera Health, as mentioned,
only one member proposal needs to be in NR for
this discount.  It is
possible to apply for it. Similarly,
in insurance, we have a deductible option available to us.
That is, if
we look at it now, in HDS,
we know that a one-year premium comes at ₹
1450 per 10 lakh. Let's
assume that we
put the deductible up. Our premium will be
reduced to ₹11262. After deducting ₹000, the
premium will be
reduced again to ₹410. That is,
after saying deduct, our premium is
reduced again. That is,
I can take a net expense from my hand
or deduct, which
means that I take expenses up to ₹000 from
my hand. After that, we just have to
give the insurance coverage that comes after that to the insurance company.  So,
after taking this approach, we
only need to choose premium if we need it
.
Choosing the deductible option is an idea that is done to reduce premiums.  In this,
HDC is a warhead covered.  We
can set the deduct option as described above.  The ICC
department, as well as Care Health, do not have this
deduction option available to them
.  Similarly,
one of the main things we should ask when we take out a policy is whether there is a
sub-limit for our room or ISIC
.  Because if there are restrictions on this room, as
we
mentioned, if we have a policy that
covers a single flight room when we are admitted, if we have to
take a suite room and have to take a deluxe room, we will have a copayment
sub-limit.
So when you take out health insurance as your main policy,
you can ask if there is any sub-limit for the room.
Then we can choose a room from these four companies
.  There
are no restrictions on the room.  Similarly, even though
we have ICU charges, there is no sub-
limit.
We
can use it up to Sosh.  So, the main
thing to pay attention to when taking out health insurance is the price.  Because
our
treatment expenses are
related to the room rent.  So, try
choosing the policies that have room for you now
.  Next, we'll take a look at the
bonus.   After
adding the bonus, we
have now taken out a policy.  If we don't make any
claims, we
get even more doubts like this.
That's what we mean by bonus
.
If you look at the HDC information here, you will find that the HDC Optima Secure has
a feature that provides coverage from day one to day two
.
This means that after taking 10 lakhs, we
get coverage from day one to day X.  And with that, after
two years, we will have a
maximum of one forex coverage
.  That means, if a
person takes out 10 lakhs, they will get 40 lakhs as a bonus after two years if they
take out HDC's Optima Secure
.  If we
look at ICC Elevative, we can see
that the
feature we mentioned earlier, 2S coverage,
is an inbuilt feature. If we look at HDC Argo,
we can see that what
they provide is inbuilt and if we
take it for 10 lakhs, it becomes 20 lakhs
.  That means it keeps increasing by lakhs every year.
But one of these, called a power
boost,
has killed a rider.  So, once we have added this,
we will get our bonus added like this every year, unlimited times, like 10, 20, 30.
This bonus will continue
to increase whether there is a claim or not.  When
we take out a policy now, we pay attention to a rider called Power Booster. Try to check if
there is a rider called Power Booster
.
Similarly, if we look at Niva, we get
10A coverage. If the ratio of Niva is
3.4 in black, we get 10, that is, if the
policy is for 10 lakhs, it will
become one crore. It increases by 100 percent every year for 10 years. If we
look at Care Health, as mentioned
earlier, as mentioned in ICC, it is
inbuilt and gives 100% along with it.
They have killed the rider called infinity bonus.
So, after adding this rider,
we will have to add the bonus every year, which is
ten, 20, 30, 40, and so on, as
infinity.
These are the
things that we need to pay attention to in the case of bonus. When
we take it, check whether these riders are there.
Similarly, one thing that we need to mention is the
restoration feature. If
we look at this, that is, what we
mean by restoration is that we
think that we have a policy of 10 lakhs. Even after using this 10 lakhs, we can use it
again and again in
unlimited times.  10
lakhs will be added like this. If we look at
this feature in our health insurance policy, it is
given to us as unlimited,
but it is a rider, that is, it
comes to us as in-built one time, but if we
add the rider, we will get
unlimited time. If we add 10 lakhs as a rider,
we will get unlimited times. If we
add it as a rider,
we will get unlimited times
in-built, even though IC, IC and Navop are in Kerala.  That means,
after using 10 lakhs, now
one person in a family has used 10 lakhs, and
another person can use this 10 lakhs again,
unlimited times, for everyone
.
Restoration is also available in these policies.
Similarly, another thing we need to pay attention to is what is
called consumable coverage.  That means
there are non-medical items like cotton swabs, syringes, and gloves, and
we cover these items in health insurance.  But to cover this,
we only get it if we add an extra rider, optional coverage, to it.  It comes with HD
surround sound built-in
.  We don't need to add a separate rider
.  It's
called a protected benefit.  So, just because we add it up, it doesn't
cost us 100% of our money or expenses
.  If you are in IC Salvate, once you
add a rider called Claim Protector,
you will get coverage for these types of consumable items. If you are in
Non-Medical Items
Niwap, you need to
add a rider called Safe Guard Plus.  But
we only get these non-medical
items covered.  If we
look at Kera Health,
we need to add a rider called Claim Shield.
But we only cover these non-medical
items.
So, let's remember these riders as we say this
.
The riders in each of these companies are the riders we need to add, even if they are not important.  So
these are the
things we need to pay attention to when it comes to consumable coverage.
Then another feature I've included here
is that if you
look at the HD version of it and it says "Special Coverage," you'll
see a rider that says "Limitless Coverage."
That means, once we add this rider,
we can use it no matter how big the lifetime expense is
.
This is what is meant by unlimited coverage
.  That is, if we face
treatment expenses of Rs. 10 lakh or Rs. 1 crore,
we will
be able to claim the benefit once in a lifetime because we have this rider. If we look at IC Elevate, there is
an option called Infinite Care.  Just like
we saw with HDC, we can claim
once in our lifetime, no matter how big the
claim is
.
We have to add it separately as a rider
.  Similarly, in this, we
are shown an option called "unlimited option in ISIS".  If
we choose this option, we will have
unlimited coverage for all our claims, as we previously saw, if
we take this unlimited option, we will continue to receive
unlimited coverage for all our claims
.  That means, if we
earn a few lakhs to a crore rupees, we can use it unlimited times in the
same year, no matter how much we earn
.
Now, if we look at Navop, this plan is
famous because it has this unlimited feature. Once we
take it, we can see
three options: 5 lakh, 10 lakh, and unlimited
.
Once we choose Unlimited, we will be able to claim no matter
how big a claim we receive in a year.
Once we have chosen this option, the variant we should take is Black. If we
look in Kerala, there is
a rider that says Unlimited Coir.  So, once we have
added this rider, as we
saw earlier, we can claim for any illness, no matter
how big the expense, no matter
how big the expense
.  It's only once in a lifetime, and
we've finally brought an unlimited
option
.  So, once we add that rider,
we can claim unlimited times, no matter how big a claim we receive in a year, just like we saw in the ratio of 3.
So, these are the features that are
currently trending when taking a policy.
Try to confirm whether each of these riders is in your policy. Then the
next thing we take is
about pre-post hospitalization, that is,
we
can claim the expenses before being admitted to the hospital and the bills after being discharged from the hospital. So, if we
look at HDSAs, it is 60-180,
that is, the bills before being admitted and up to
180 days after being discharged. If it is in
ICICI, it
is 90-180, if it is in Nevop, it is 60-180, if it is
in Kerala, it is 60-90 days,
that is, we can claim the bills before being admitted and up to
90 days after being discharged. Then
we should pay
special attention to it.
Try to choose policies that come with more and more. Pre-
post is also something that we take last.
Waiting period is an important
thing that we should pay attention to after we have looked at the insurance. It is very important that we mention if we have any pre-existing
conditions. Once we
take a policy,
our policy
becomes active after 30 days. However, as mentioned in accident cases,
no waiting period is applicable. And as
mentioned, for
some illnesses, it is
said in the waiting insurance for 24 months for two years.  I'm
giving you a list here, but we can only get insurance coverage for these illnesses
after two years
.  These features are the
same in every company.  Similarly, if
we currently
have any pre-existing conditions, the insurance policy states 36 months
.  Here, if we look at the pre-assistant case, if we
look at the HD DC,
they have brought us a rider that says AB CD chronic care
.  That is, if you have asthma,
BP, cholesterol, diabetes, etc., then after
days, these conditions will be
covered.
After we add the rider called chronic care, if you
are on IC Elevate, we have introduced
a rider called Jump Start as mentioned above
.  There too, as
mentioned above, we will get coverage for asthma, BP, cholesterol,
diabetes, etc.  If this
rider called Jump Start has been added, not only that, but in order
to reduce the PD,
we have been told that the pre-assist IP is 36 months. If we
want, we have
an option to reduce it to two years or one year. Now, if we
look at the OP, as mentioned, we have
a big special feature here.
They are providing coverage for 145 diseases starting from the Devil.
Now, if we mention
145 diseases like BP, sugar, cholesterol,
we
get coverage starting from the Devil.
It covers 145 illnesses.   There is only
one plan in the market today that
provides coverage for 145 illnesses, starting from David.
And if you look at Kerala Health,
there is a rider called Instant Cover.  That means, if we have added this rider called Instant Care, we will get coverage for asthma, BP, cholesterol,
diabetes, and hypothyroidism
after 30 days.
Especially,
we, the riders, should be careful to take the
supplements if we have any illnesses like this
.
And just like any other insurance,
all the features like modern treatment, AYUSH treatment, health checkup, ambulance coverage, day care treatment, etc. are covered in these policies
.  I won't go into detail and make comparisons
.  The reason is that the
video keeps getting longer and longer.
Of course, if you
have NR status,
try to consider these four policies in particular.  So if you have any questions
about this policy,
I'll
give you my WhatsApp number below.  Then
you can send a message to it
or call it
.  Of course I will
answer.  Thank you.
Dear friends, if you like Katukumani's videos, you should join us
.